They were seven…and they fought like seven hundred!
The Magnificent Seven is a western, action,
adventure film directed by John Sturges.
An oppressed Mexican peasant village hires seven
gunfighters to help defend their homes.
Chris Adams, played by Yul Brynner.
Calvera, played by Eli Wallach.
Vin, played by Steve McQueen.
Bernardo O'Reilly, played by Charles Bronson.
Lee, played by Robert Vaughn.
Harry Luck, played by Brad Dexter.
The Magnificent Seven is a 1960 American Western film directed by John Sturges.
The screenplay, credited to William Roberts, is a remake – in an Old West-style – of Akira Kurosawa's 1954
Japanese film Seven Samurai (itself initially released in the United States as The Magnificent Seven).
The ensemble cast includes Yul Brynner, Steve McQueen, Charles Bronson, Robert Vaughn, Brad Dexter, James Coburn, and Horst Buchholz as a
group of seven gunfighters hired to protect a small village in Mexico from a group of marauding bandits led by Eli Wallach.
The film was released by United Artists on October 12, 1960, becoming both a critical and commercial
success and has been appraised as one of the greatest films of the Western genre.
It spawned three sequels, a television series that aired
from 1998 to 2000, and a 2016 film remake.
Elmer Bernstein's film score was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Original Score and is
listed on the American Film Institute's list of the top 25 American film scores.
In 2013, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of friendship, gunslinger, village, horse, remake.